Welcome to this demonstration of Tetris in Ada, showcasing the DEGAS replacement runtime for regression testing.
While dtetris provides an interactive experience, ttetris is specifically designed for automated testing.
We start with ttetris running under the standard Ada runtime. Notice the slow, real-time progression.
The game relies on wall-clock time for task scheduling and delays, which can be inefficient for testing.
Now, we switch to the DEGAS runtime. DEGAS enables high-speed testing by replacing wall-clock time with simulated time.
By intercepting pthread calls via LD_PRELOAD, DEGAS eliminates real-world waiting from Ada delay calls.
The result is instantaneous evaluation. This allows us to run complex test suites in a fraction of the time.
Beyond speed, DEGAS provides a deterministic and reproducible event order, ensuring that test results remain consistent.
Finally, we see ttetris running again without DEGAS. Observe the non-determinism as the results differ each time.
This variability makes regression testing unreliable. With DEGAS, we gain both speed and total reproducibility.